Guide to the William Saroyan Correspondence with Goldie Weisberg, 1930-1938
Department of Special Collections
Saroyan, William, 1908-. Correspondence with Goldie Weisberg,
1930-1938
M1155
Saroyan, William, 1908-
.25 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
The collection consists of 55 letters from Saroyan totaling 153 pages and 36 letters and cards from Weisberg. The letters are intensely literary and show a side of Saroyan that becomes virtually invisible to documentation after his popular success in 1934. (Notes taken from dealer Peter B. Howard's description)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None.
Acquisition Information
Purchased, 2000.
Biography
Goldie Weisberg was a fellow writer whose work Saroyan had discovered in a literary magzine. Saroyan initiated the correspondence, which focuses on their respective reading, writing, and work lives.
Collection Scope and Content Summary
The collection consists of 55 letters from Saroyan totaling 153 pages and 36 letters and cards from Weisberg. The letters are intensely literary and show a side of Saroyan that becomes virtually invisible to documentation after his popular success in 1934. (Notes taken from dealer Peter B. Howard's description)
Access Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Weisberg, Goldie.; American literature--20th century.
Collection Contents
- Series 1. William Saroyan Letters to Goldie Weisberg
  - Saroyan, William. TLS to Goldie Weisberg,1930 Oct. 23, 1p (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Saroyan, William. TLS to Goldie Weisberg,1930 Oct. 30, 1p (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Saroyan, William. TLS to Goldie Weisberg,1930 Nov. 3, 3pp (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Saroyan, William. TLS to Goldie Weisberg,1930 Nov. 11, 4 half-sheets (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Saroyan, William. TLS to Goldie Weisberg,1930 Nov. 13, 3pp (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Saroyan, William. TLS to Goldie Weisberg,1930 Nov. 14, 3pp (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Saroyan, William. TLS to Goldie Weisberg,1930 Nov. 18, 2+ half-sheets (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Saroyan, William. TLS to Goldie Weisberg,1930 Nov. 19, 1 p (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Saroyan, William. TLS to Goldie Weisberg,1930 Nov. 20, 3 pp (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Saroyan, William. TLS to Goldie Weisberg,1930 Nov. 21, 1p (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Saroyan, William. TLS to Goldie Weisberg,1930 Nov. 22, 3pp (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Saroyan, William. TLS to Goldie Weisberg,1930 Nov. 24, 2pp (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Saroyan, William. TLS to Goldie Weisberg,1930 Nov. 25, 2pp (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Saroyan, William. TLS to Goldie Weisberg,1930 Nov. 26, 1p (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Saroyan, William. TLS to Goldie Weisberg,1930 Dec. 1, 4+ pp (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Saroyan, William. TLS to Goldie Weisberg,1930 Dec. 2, 2 half-sheets (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Saroyan, William. TLS to Goldie Weisberg,1930 Dec. 11, 1p (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Saroyan, William. TLS to Goldie Weisberg,1930 Dec. 15, 2pp (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Saroyan, William. TLS to Goldie Weisberg,1930 Dec. 16, 5pp (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Saroyan, William. TLS to Goldie Weisberg,1930 Dec. 17, 2pp (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Saroyan, William. TLS to Goldie Weisberg,1930 Dec. 18, 1.5pp (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Saroyan, William. TLS to Goldie Weisberg,1930 Dec. 19, 2pp (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Saroyan, William. ALS to Goldie Weisberg,1930 Dec. 22, 2pp (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Saroyan, William. TLS to Goldie Weisberg,1930 Dec. 26, 2pp (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Saroyan, William. TLS to Goldie Weisberg,1930 Dec. 28, 3pp (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Saroyan, William. TLS to Goldie Weisberg,1930 Dec. 29, 1/3p (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Saroyan, William. TLS to Goldie Weisberg,1931 Jan. 2, 4pp (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Saroyan, William. TLS to Goldie Weisberg,1931 Jan. 22, 4pp "Thursday," Jan. 15 or (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Saroyan, William. TLS to Goldie Weisberg,1931 Jan. 29, 6pp (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Saroyan, William. TLS to Goldie Weisberg,[1931 Jan.?], 1 1/4 p, "Sunday," ny (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Saroyan, William. TLS to Goldie Weisberg,1931 Feb. 10, 7pp (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Saroyan, William. TLS to Goldie Weisberg,1931 Feb. 12, 6pp (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Saroyan, William. TLS to Goldie Weisberg,1931 Feb. 16, 1/3p (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Saroyan, William. TLS to Goldie Weisberg,1931 Feb. 16, 2 1/2pp (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Saroyan, William. TLS to Goldie Weisberg,1931 Feb. 17, 3pp (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Saroyan, William. TLS to Goldie Weisberg,1931 Feb. 27, 3 1/2pp (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Saroyan, William. TLS to Goldie Weisberg,1931 Feb. 28, 4pp (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Saroyan, William. TLS to Goldie Weisberg,1931 Mar. 2, 2 1/2pp (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Saroyan, William. TLS to Goldie Weisberg,1931 Mar. 5, 4pp (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Saroyan, William. TLS to Goldie Weisberg,1931 Mar. 9, 4pp (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Saroyan, William. TLS to Goldie Weisberg,1931 Mar. 11, 3pp (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Saroyan, William. TLS to Goldie Weisberg,1931 Mar. 12, 1p (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Saroyan, William. TLS to Goldie Weisberg,1931 Mar. 13, 1 1/2pp (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Saroyan, William. TLS to Goldie Weisberg,1931 Mar. 25, 6pp (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Saroyan, William. TLS to Goldie Weisberg,1931 Mar. 29, 4pp (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Saroyan, William. TLS to Goldie Weisberg,1931 Apr. 5, 4pp (Box 5, Folder 46)
  - Saroyan, William. TLS to Goldie Weisberg,1931 Apr. [6?], 5pp, "Monday," (Box 5, Folder 47)
  - Saroyan, William. TLS to Goldie Weisberg,[1931 Apr. 13?], 3pp, "Monday," (Box 5, Folder 48)
  - Saroyan, William. TLS to Goldie Weisberg,[1931 Apr. 24?], 1/2 p, "Friday," Apr. 17 or (Box 5, Folder 49)
  - Saroyan, William. TLS to Goldie Weisberg,1931 Apr. 30, 3pp (Box 5, Folder 50)
  - Saroyan, William. TLS to Goldie Weisberg,[1931 May 7?], 1p, "Friday," (Box 5, Folder 51)
  - Saroyan, William. TLS to Goldie Weisberg,1933 May 8, 7pp (Box 5, Folder 52)
  - Saroyan, William. TLS to Goldie Weisberg,1933 June 27, 5+pp (Box 5, Folder 53)
  - Saroyan, William. TLS to Goldie Weisberg,1934 Jan 31, 2pp (Box 5, Folder 54)
  - Saroyan, William. TLS to Goldie Weisberg,1934 May 10, 1/3p (Box 5, Folder 55)
  - Saroyan, William. TLS to Goldie Weisberg,1934 Sept. 13, 1p (Box 5, Folder 56)
  - nd (Box 6, Folder 810)
  - nd (Box 7, Folder 0)
- Series 2. Goldie Weisberg letters to William Saroyan
  - Weisberg, Goldie. ALS to William Saroyan,1930 Oct. 29, 1p (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Weisberg, Goldie. ALS to William Saroyan,1930 Nov. 10, 4pp (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Weisberg, Goldie. ALS to William Saroyan, [1930 Oct. 11?], envelope: 1p (Box 8, Folder 3)
    "Wednesday"
  - Weisberg, Goldie. ALS to William Saroyan,1930 Nov. 23, 6pp + 1p (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Weisberg, Goldie. ALS to William Saroyan,1930 Nov. 29, 5pp, "Saturday," envelope: (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Weisberg, Goldie. ALS to William Saroyan,1930 Dec. 14, 4pp, "Sunday," envelope: (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Christmas card, 1930 Dec. 22 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Weisberg, Goldie. ALS to William Saroyan,1930 Dec. 30, 4pp, "Monday," envelope: (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Weisberg, Goldie. TLS to William Saroyan,1931 Jan. 13, 3 1/2pp, envelope: (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Weisberg, Goldie. TLS to William Saroyan,1931 Jan. 16, 2pp (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Weisberg, Goldie. TLS to William Saroyan,1931 Jan. 27, 3pp (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Weisberg, Goldie. TLS to William Saroyan,1931 Feb. 8, 2pp, envelope: (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Weisberg, Goldie. TLS to William Saroyan,1931 Feb. 14, 6pp (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Weisberg, Goldie. ALS to William Saroyan,1931 Feb. 26, 8pp, envelope: (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Weisberg, Goldie. TLS to William Saroyan,1931 Mar. 23, 4 1/2pp, envelope: (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Weisberg, Goldie. TLS to William Saroyan,1931 Mar. 14, 5pp, envelope: (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Weisberg, Goldie. ALS to William Saroyan,1931 Mar. 26, 2pp, clipping enclosed, envelope: (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Weisberg, Goldie. TLS to William Saroyan,1931 Apr. 12, 1 1/2pp, envelope: (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Weisberg, Goldie. ALS to William Saroyan,1931 Apr. 18, 4pp, envelope: (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Weisberg, Goldie. TLS to William Saroyan,1931 May 15, 2pp, envelope: (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Weisberg, Goldie. ALS to William Saroyan,1931 July 2, 2pp, envelope: (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - Weisberg, Goldie. TLS to William Saroyan,1931 July 5, 1 1/3pp, envelope: (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - Weisberg, Goldie. ALS to William Saroyan,1931 July 29, 2pp (Box 12, Folder 23)
  - Weisberg, Goldie. ALS to William Saroyan,1931 Aug. 26, 2pp, envelope: (Box 12, Folder 24)
  - Weisberg, Goldie. TLS to William Saroyan,1931 Sept. 14, 1p, envelope: (Box 12, Folder 25)
  - Weisberg, Goldie. TLS to William Saroyan,1931 Sept. 25, 2pp, envelope: (Box 12, Folder 26)
  - Christmas card, 1931 Dec. 21 (Box 12, Folder 27)
  - Weisberg, Goldie. TLS to William Saroyan,[1930 or 1931], 2pp, "Saturday night," no month or year (Box 12, Folder 28)
  - ANS, no month or year, [1930 or 1931] (Box 12, Folder 29)
  - Weisberg, Goldie. TLS to William Saroyan,1938 Feb. 18, 1p (Box 13, Folder 30)
  - Weisberg, Goldie. TLS to William Saroyan,1938 Apr. 19, 1p (Box 13, Folder 31)
  - Weisberg, Goldie. TLS to William Saroyan,1938 May 22, 1p (Box 13, Folder 32)
  - Weisberg, Goldie. TLS to William Saroyan,1938 June 15, 1p (Box 13, Folder 33)
  - Weisberg, Goldie. TLS to William Saroyan,1938 July 19, 1p (Box 13, Folder 34)
  - Weisberg, Goldie. TLS to William Saroyan,1938 Sept. 6, 1p (Box 13, Folder 35)
  - Weisberg, Goldie. TLS to William Saroyan,1938 Sept. 17, 1p (Box 13, Folder 36)